start with a right triangle with legs of
length a b and a hypotenuse of length C
first take a copy of this triangle and
scale up by the value B
next take another copy of the triangle
and scale up by the value a
because the leg lengths a b and b a are
equal we see that the triangles fit
together this way and because the two
non-right angles in the original
triangle are complementary this larger
triangle we formed is a right triangle
now scale the original triangle up one
more time by the value C we now have two
right triangles with equal leg lengths
this means that the two triangles are
congruent and so their hypotenuse
lengths are equal
therefore a squared plus b squared must
be equal to c squared where A and B are
the legs of a right triangle and C is
the hypotenuse this is the Pythagorean
theorem